♪In the face of turmoil♪
♪혼란에 직면해서♪
♪Your roots hold firmly♪
♪당신의 뿌리는 굳건히 자리잡고 있습니다♪
♪To this piece of land♪
♪이 땅으로♪
♪Chasing after the waves♪
♪파도를 쫓아♪
♪My leaves flutter across♪
♪나의 나뭇잎이 펄럭인다♪
♪The horizon♪
♪수평선♪
♪Gazing from afar♪
♪멀리서 바라보며♪
♪At the end of the world♪
♪세상의 끝에서♪
♪Is eternity♪
♪영원하다♪
♪When we meet and then part♪
♪만나고 헤어질 때♪
♪When we rely on each other and then drift apart♪
♪서로 의지 하다가 멀어질 때♪
♪I have never forgotten♪
♪잊어버린 적 없어♪
♪As the glinting of swords cut♪
♪검의 반짝임이 끊어지듯이♪
♪Through the mottled sky♪
♪얼룩덜룩한 하늘을 통해♪
♪The falling dreams♪
♪떨어지는 꿈들♪
♪Shatter in the wind♪
♪바람에 부서지네♪
♪As the wind breaks through the waves♪
♪바람이 파도를 가르듯♪
♪It watches thousands of sails cross♪
♪수천 개의 돛이 교차하는 모습을 지켜봅니다♪
♪The vast land and the boundless sea♪
♪광활한 대지와 끝없는 바다♪
♪Armor and red robes flying high♪
♪갑옷과 붉은 로브가 높이 날아오르네♪
♪In the face of bitterness, intense emotions, and joyful adventure♪
♪씁쓸함과 강렬한 감정, 그리고 즐거운 모험에 맞서 ♪
♪I only wish you to be by my side♪
♪당신이 내 곁에만 있기를 바랍니다♪
♪Making the most of what life offers♪
♪인생이 제공하는 것을 최대한 활용하기♪
♪Like towering trees with interconnected roots, I'll accompany you to the ends♪
♪뿌리가 얽힌 우뚝 솟은 나무처럼 끝까지 함께하겠습니다♪
♪Watching fireflies land on our shoulders♪
♪ 어깨에 앉는 반딧불이를 바라보며 ♪
♪No regrets, no doubts in this world♪
♪이 세상에는 후회도 의심도 없어♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=사랑의 원더랜드=
=Episode 16=
=에피소드 16=
Li Ni didn't enter Luoyang City with his troops.
Li Ni는 그의 군대와 함께 Luoyang City에 들어가지 않았습니다 .
Instead, they set up camp.
대신 그들은 캠프를 세웠습니다.
Why do you think they did so?
그들이 왜 그렇게 했다고 생각합니까?
According to the fold
접힌 부분에 따르면
that Li Ni had sent to Father,
리니가 아버지께 보낸 편지,
it was inconvenient for the army to enter the city.
군대가 도시에 들어가는 것은 불편했습니다 .
He set up camp outside
그는 밖에 캠프를 세웠다
so that it's easier to conduct military operations.
군사 작전을 수행하기가 더 쉬워졌습니다 .
It's obvious that he suffered defeat and wasn't willing to enter the city.
그가 패배를 당하고 도시에 들어가고 싶지 않은 것은 분명합니다.
He still dared to submit a fold to Father
그는 여전히 아버지에게 감히 양을 제출했습니다
saying that he wanted to reclaim Xichang.
그는 Xichang을 되찾고 싶다고 말했습니다 .
Jun,
준,
Young Master Cui is dead.
최영선생이 죽었습니다.
Cui Yi must be enraged by now.
Cui Yi는 지금쯤 분노했을 것입니다.
It's good that he's outside the city.
그가 도시 밖에 있다는 것이 좋습니다.
If not,
그렇지 않다면,
Luoyang City will be implicated
낙양시가 연루될 것이다
when the Cui Army arrives.
Cui 군대가 도착할 때.
(To Uncle)
(삼촌에게)
Father, since His Highness had sent you a letter,
아버지, 전하께서 편지를 보내셨으니,
I assume he found a way
내 생각엔 그가 방법을 찾은 것 같아
to conquer Xichang.
시창(Xichang)을 정복하기 위해.
In the letter, Li Ni hoped
편지에서 Li Ni는 희망했습니다.
that I could
내가 할 수 있다고
contact the old subjects of the previous rule
이전 규칙의 이전 주제에 문의하십시오.
and spread the news of Sun Jing's failed conquest
그리고 손징의 정복 실패 소식을 퍼뜨렸다.
in Baiyue.
바이웨에.
He wanted the people to think
그는 사람들이 생각하기를 원했습니다.
that Sun Jing suffered a major defeat.
Sun Jing은 큰 패배를 겪었습니다.
It's best if it causes a hike in food prices.
식량 가격이 인상 된다면 가장 좋습니다 .
This way, people's hearts will be shaken.
그러면 사람의 마음이 흔들릴 것입니다.
Father,
아버지,
what do you think His Highness is up to?
전하께서 무엇을 하고 계시다고 생각하시나요?
He's crafty and adaptable to change.
그는 교활하고 변화에 적응력이 뛰어납니다.
I can't tell either.
나도 말할 수 없습니다.
However,
하지만,
it seems that he intends to cause chaos in the city.
그는 도시에 혼란을 일으키려 는 것 같습니다 .
He'll get his opportunity
그 사람은 기회를 얻게 될 거야
when the city is in chaos.
도시가 혼란에 빠졌을 때.
♪Reminiscing about that first moment♪
♪첫 순간을 회상하며♪
♪Waiting for my inner scars to heal♪
♪내면의 상처가 아물기를 기다리며♪
♪Holding the lone spark of the opposite shore♪
♪ 저편 해안의 외로운 불꽃을 품고 ♪
♪Dwelling on your existence♪
♪당신의 존재에 머물다♪
♪My heart longs for you♪
♪내 마음은 당신을 그리워해요♪
♪It still beats for you after you break it♪
♪ 부러뜨린 후에도 여전히 두근두근합니다 ♪
♪I still remember our past♪
♪아직도 우리의 과거를 기억해요♪
♪I turned around and glanced at you♪
♪뒤돌아서 당신을 바라보았어요♪
♪It's hard to part with you♪
♪너와 헤어지기 힘들다♪
♪I once loved because of you♪
♪한때 너 때문에 사랑했었어♪
♪If only I could cherish this momentary warmth♪
♪이 순간의 따뜻함을 간직할 수만 있다면 ♪
Thank you.
감사합니다.
It doesn't hurt, right?
아프지 않죠?
No.
아니요.
♪If only I could live this moment for you♪
♪이 순간을 당신을 위해 살 수만 있다면 ♪
♪My memory sinks, and my heart broken♪
♪기억이 가라앉고 마음이 아프네요♪
♪Life and death mean nothing♪
♪삶과 죽음은 아무 의미가 없습니다♪
♪If only I could return to your side♪
♪내가 당신 곁으로 돌아갈 수만 있다면♪
♪Stopping by beside you♪
♪네 옆에 들러♪
♪It's hard to part with you♪
♪너와 헤어지기 힘들다♪
♪I once loved because of you♪
♪한때 너 때문에 사랑했었어♪
♪If only I could cherish this momentary warmth♪
♪이 순간의 따뜻함을 간직할 수만 있다면 ♪
♪If only I could live this moment for you♪
♪이 순간을 당신을 위해 살 수만 있다면
♪My memory sinks, and my heart broken♪
♪기억이 가라앉고 마음이 아프네요♪
♪Life and death mean nothing♪
♪삶과 죽음은 아무 의미가 없습니다♪
♪If only I could return to your side♪
♪내가 당신 곁으로 돌아갈 수만 있다면♪
♪Stopping by beside you♪
♪네 옆에 들러♪
You want to play chess?
체스를 두고 싶나요?
I can get you a new set.
새 세트를 가져다 드릴 수 있어요.
Why are you going through all this effort just to make them yourself?
왜 직접 만들기 위해 이 모든 노력을 기울이시나요 ?
Young Master loved playing chess.
Young Master는 체스를 좋아했습니다.
I once promised him
나는 한때 그에게 약속했다.
that I would make him
내가 그 사람을 만들겠다고
a set of chess pieces.
체스 말 세트.
Ying,
잉,
Father finally promised us
아버지는 마침내 우리에게 약속하셨다.
that we could lead an army and leave Yingzhou.
우리가 군대를 이끌고 영저우를 떠날 수 있다는 것이었습니다.
Opportunities slip away quickly.
기회는 빨리 사라져 버립니다.
We mustn't miss out on this opportunity.
우리는 이 기회를 놓치지 말아야 합니다.
Really?
정말?
Ying,
잉,
I know.
알아요.
This is what you always desired.
이것이 당신이 항상 원했던 것입니다.
Ever since Sun Jing started a revolt,
손징이 반란을 일으킨 이후부터
you wanted to
당신은 원했다
vie for the world
세계를 위해 경쟁하다
and dominate the realm.
그리고 왕국을 지배하세요.
Young Master,
젊은 스승님,
you do know me well.
당신은 나를 잘 알고 있습니다.
Ying, your goal
잉, 너의 목표
is my goal.
내 목표입니다.
As long as there's something you wish to achieve,
이루고 싶은 것이 있다면 ,
I'll definitely do my best
반드시 최선을 다하겠습니다
to help you achieve it.
당신이 그것을 달성하도록 돕기 위해.
(Thank you, Young Master.)
(고마워요, 영 선생님.)
(Since I've fulfilled my end of the bargain,)
(나는 거래의 목적을 달성했기 때문에)
(you should remember)
(당신은 기억해야합니다)
your end of the bargain too.
너도 거래는 끝났어.
Of course I do.
물론이죠.
Young Master,
젊은 스승님,
you wanted a set of chess pieces.
당신은 체스 말 세트를 원했습니다.
Young Master, don't worry.
젊은 선생님, 걱정하지 마세요.
I'll definitely make you an entire set
꼭 한 세트로 만들어 드릴게요
when I have free time
내가 자유시간이 있을 때
out there.
저 밖에.
That's unnecessary.
그것은 불필요합니다.
I just need you to select the jade pieces personally.
옥 조각을 개인적으로 선택해 주시기만 하면 됩니다 .
It's the same when I tell the jade craftsman
옥장인에게 말할 때도 마찬가지다.
to make it for me.
나를 위해 만들어 주려고.
That won't do.
그러면 안 됩니다.
I must make them myself.
내가 직접 만들어야 해요.
They represent my sincerity.
그것은 나의 진심을 나타냅니다.
But now,
그러나 지금,
I'm afraid I have no chance
기회가 없을까 봐
to give it to him myself.
그에게 직접 주려고.
For my sake,
나를 위해서,
Young Master took the shot and fell into the river.
Young Master는 총을 맞고 강에 빠졌습니다.
I can't even recover his body.
나는 그의 시신조차 회복할 수 없다.
Now,
지금,
I can only erect a tomb for him
나는 그를 위해 무덤을 세울 수 밖에 없습니다.
and make him a set of chess pieces
그리고 그에게 체스 말 세트를 만들어 주세요
as a burial gift.
장례식 선물로.
What?
무엇?
Can't I even do that now?
지금은 그것조차 할 수 없나요?
Must you say such hurtful words?
그런 상처 주는 말을 해야 합니까?
Hurtful?
해로운가?
Young Master died for my sake.
젊은 스승님은 나를 위해 돌아가셨습니다.
Shouldn't I grieve his loss?
그의 상실을 슬퍼해야 하지 않나요?
Shouldn't I be upset that he's gone?
그 사람이 떠났다고 해서 화를 내야 하는 것 아닌가?
So, you're still blaming me for not saving your young master, right?
그럼 아직도 어린 스승님을 구하지 못했다고 나를 탓하고 계시는 거죠?
That's right!
좋아요!
So, you're heartbroken,
그러니 당신은 마음이 상했군요.
and you wish that you could die with him, right?
그리고 당신도 그 사람과 함께 죽을 수 있었으면 좋겠어요 , 그렇죠?
That's right!
좋아요!
Li Ni,
리 니,
listen up.
잘 들어.
I was lying to you all along.
나는 줄곧 당신에게 거짓말을 하고 있었습니다.
I fell for
나는 반했다
Young Master long ago.
오래 전 젊은 스승님.
I was lying to you from the start.
나는 처음부터 당신에게 거짓말을 하고 있었습니다.
I was the one who duped you
너를 속인 건 나였어
into heading to Xichang.
시창으로 향합니다.
As for the incident in Tong Pass,
통고개 사건을 보면,
I plotted that
나는 그것을 음모했다
with Young Master long ago.
오래전 영스승님과 함께.
I did so to trick you.
당신을 속이려고 그랬어요.
I wanted to trick you so that you would suffer a major defeat.
나는 당신을 속여 큰 패배를 당하게 만들고 싶었습니다.
But now, Young Master is dead.
하지만 이제 영 마스터는 죽었습니다.
I've lost all hope.
나는 모든 희망을 잃었습니다.
I don't want to deceive you anymore!
더 이상 당신을 속이고 싶지 않아요!
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Just kill me!
그냥 나를 죽여라!
You truly know
당신은 정말로 알고 있습니다
how to break my heart.
내 마음을 아프게 하는 방법.
That's why you said that to me.
그래서 당신이 나에게 그런 말을 한 것입니다.
I know I maligned you
내가 당신을 욕했다는 걸 알아요
and broke your heart.
그리고 당신의 마음을 아프게했습니다.
That's why you're saying that to break my heart.
그래서 당신이 내 마음을 아프게 하려고 그런 말을 하는 거죠.
Am I right?
내가 맞나요?
I'm heartbroken?
나 상심했어?
Why should I be heartbroken?
왜 내가 상심해야 합니까?
I was lying to you all along.
나는 줄곧 당신에게 거짓말을 하고 있었습니다.
I was lying to you.
나는 당신에게 거짓말을 하고 있었습니다.
I never fancied you.
나는 당신을 좋아한 적이 없습니다.
Everything was fake.
모든 것이 가짜였습니다.
But my feelings for you are true.
하지만 당신에 대한 내 감정은 사실이에요.
I don't care if you fancy your young master or not.
당신 이 젊은 주인을 좋아하든 말든 상관하지 않습니다 .
I have genuine feelings for you.
나는 당신에 대한 진정한 감정을 가지고 있습니다.
When I first met you,
처음 만났을 때,
you kicked me into the well.
당신은 나를 우물에 발로 차버렸어요.
Back then, I thought
그때 나는 생각했다.
that I must get back
내가 다시 돌아가야 한다는 걸
at the person
그 사람에게
who kicked me into the well.
나를 우물에 밀어 넣은 사람.
But after that, we met again.
그런데 그 이후에 다시 만났어요.
Initially, I could seek revenge against you.
처음에는 나는 당신에게 복수할 수도 있었습니다.
But I didn't do so.
그러나 나는 그렇게 하지 않았습니다.
I hesitated.
나는 망설였다.
I didn't know why either.
나도 그 이유를 몰랐다.
When we were in Taiqing Palace,
우리가 태청궁에 있을 때,
I made a bet with you.
나는 당신과 내기를 했습니다.
In the end, I lost to you.
결국 나는 당신에게 졌습니다.
But in my heart...
하지만 내 마음속에는...
In my heart,
내 마음 속에,
there was an indescribable happiness.
이루 말할 수 없는 행복이 있었습니다.
It's because I finally know
비로소 알게 됐으니까
that you fancy me too.
너도 나 좋아한다고.
You had feelings for me too.
당신도 나에 대한 감정을 갖고 있었어요.
So, when you said that you were lying to me,
그래서 당신 이 나에게 거짓말을 했다고 말했을 때,
that you didn't fancy me,
당신이 나를 좋아하지 않았다는 것,
that everything in the past was fake,
과거의 모든 것은 가짜였다고,
I would never believe in them.
나는 결코 그들을 믿지 않을 것입니다.
It's because
왜냐하면
your feelings for me are true.
나에 대한 당신의 감정은 사실입니다.
No matter how angry you are at me,
나한테 아무리 화를 내도
don't take it out on your body.
몸에 꺼내지 마세요.
You're injured.
당신은 부상을 입었습니다.
Remember to take your medicine.
약을 복용하는 것을 잊지 마십시오.
Don't skip your meals.
식사를 거르지 마십시오.
Why isn't it sprouting yet?
왜 아직 싹이 나지 않는 걸까요?
Could it be that the weather is too cold?
날씨가 너무 추워서 그럴까요 ?
Taozi!
도자!
Long time no see.
오랜만이에요.
We've finally met again.
우리 드디어 다시 만났어요.
Taozi.
도자.
Taozi, why are you ignoring me again?
타오즈야, 왜 또 나를 무시하는 거야?
Let me help you out.
제가 도와드리겠습니다.
Taozi?
도자?
(Milk Candy) Seems like that mouse was here again.
(밀크캔디) 저 쥐가 또 여기 있었던 것 같아요.
You throw a tantrum
당신은 짜증을 낸다
whenever he's here.
그가 여기 있을 때마다.
One's liver suffers whenever one throws a tantrum.
짜증을 낼 때마다 간이 아프다 .
I'm worried that your injury
네 부상이 걱정되네
might never heal, you know?
절대 낫지 않을 수도 있어, 알지?
Since you feel terrible,
기분이 너무 나빠서,
why don't you have some milk candy?
왜 우유사탕 안 드세요?
That mouse is something else.
그 쥐는 다른 것입니다.
He knew that you would be furious
그 사람은 네가 화낼 줄 알았어
when you see him.
당신이 그를 볼 때.
How dare he deliver the candy here?
어떻게 감히 여기에 사탕을 배달할 수 있겠어요?
Why don't you take your medicine?
약을 먹지 그래?
What's wrong with your hands?
손에 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
It's nothing. It's just some scratches.
그것은 아무것도 아니다. 그냥 약간의 긁힌 자국이 있을 뿐입니다.
Why did you do that?
왜 그런 짓을 한거야?
Even if Young Master is no longer with us now,
이제 영스승은 우리 곁에 없어도
I'm sure he'll be heartbroken when he sees you
그 사람이 당신을 보면 마음이 아플 것 같아요.
in this state from above.
이 상태에서 위에서.
Here.
여기.
Did you
당신은
argue with Li Ni just now?
지금 리니랑 논쟁?
That's right.
좋아요.
I told him off.
나는 그에게 말했다.
I said something mean to him.
나는 그에게 뭔가 나쁜 말을 했다.
But I didn't expect him
하지만 난 그 사람을 기대하지 않았어
to...
에게...
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
It's nothing.
그것은 아무것도 아니다.
Lieutenant He,
그 중위,
I know you're still angry
당신이 아직도 화난 거 알아요
that Li Ni didn't trust you.
Li Ni가 당신을 믿지 않았다는 것입니다.
You're angry that he did nothing when we were in danger.
당신은 우리가 위험에 처했을 때 그가 아무것도 하지 않은 것에 화가 났어요 .
You feel heartbroken and guilty
당신은 상심하고 죄책감을 느낍니다.
about Young Master's death.
영 마스터의 죽음에 대해.
But you can't just
하지만 그냥은 할 수 없어
keep this up.
이것을 유지하십시오.
You have to take care of your health too,
건강도 잘 챙기셔야 하고,
am I right?
내가 맞나요?
I got it. Don't worry about me.
알겠어요. 내 걱정은 하지 마세요.
We're stuck here.
우리는 여기에 갇혀 있습니다.
I'm sure Great General Cui Yi
나는 확신한다. 최이(Cui Yi) 대장군
is worried about us.
우리를 걱정하고 있습니다.
We have to think of a way
우리는 방법을 생각해야 해
to escape to Yingzhou.
영주로 탈출합니다.
Lieutenant He,
그 중위,
why don't we
우리는 왜 안 돼?
start with Li Ni?
리니부터 시작해볼까?
Take advantage of him to escape to Yingzhou.
그를 이용하여 Yingzhou로 탈출하십시오.
The little mouse wants to steal some lamp oil.
작은 생쥐는 등유를 훔치고 싶어합니다.
He failed. Thus, he tried to steal some honey.
그는 실패했다. 그래서 그는 꿀을 훔치려고 했습니다.
You only took your medicine
넌 약만 먹었잖아
without taking dinner.
저녁도 먹지 않고.
If you keep this up, your health will be affected.
계속 이런 식으로 하면 건강에 해를 끼칠 수 있습니다.
I brought you a bottle of honey.
꿀 한 병을 가져왔습니다.
I made you a flatbread too.
플랫브레드도 만들어 줬어요.
Why don't you have some?
왜 좀 없어요?
Your Highness, thanks for your concern.
전하, 걱정해주셔서 감사합니다.
But I'm not hungry.
하지만 배고프지 않아요.
Even if you're mad at me,
나한테 화를 내더라도,
you can't just starve yourself.
굶기만 할 수는 없습니다.
Your Highness, why are you so concerned about a prisoner like me?
전하, 저 같은 죄수를 왜 그렇게 걱정하시나요?
It's late now.
지금은 늦었어요.
I'm a woman while you're a man.
나는 여자이고 당신은 남자입니다.
It's inappropriate for you to be here.
당신이 여기 있는 것은 부적절해요.
You should leave.
당신은 떠나야합니다.
I just want you
난 그냥 당신을 원해요
to stay here for a few more days.
여기에 며칠 더 머물려고요.
You're not a prisoner.
당신은 죄수가 아닙니다.
Your Highness, you don't need to make up such a grand excuse.
전하, 그렇게 거창한 변명을 할 필요는 없습니다 .
Young Master is dead.
젊은 스승님은 죽었습니다.
I'm just a woman.
나는 단지 여자입니다.
You can't use me
당신은 나를 사용할 수 없습니다
to coerce the Cui Army
추이군을 강요하다
to do your bidding.
당신의 입찰을 수행합니다.
Since you said I wasn't a prisoner,
당신이 내가 포로가 아니라고 말했기 때문에
why aren't you willing to release me?
왜 나를 풀어줄 생각이 없는 거야?
It's because you're injured.
부상을 입었기 때문이죠.
I would've died anyway
어차피 죽었을 텐데
had you arrived one second later.
1초 뒤에 도착했더라면.
There's no need for you to be concerned about my injury.
내 부상에 대해 걱정할 필요는 없습니다 .
Even if you're not doing it for me,
나한테는 안 해준다고 해도,
you should do it for Taozi's sake.
Taozi를 위해 그렇게 해야 합니다.
She's anxious about
그녀는 걱정하고있다
your condition every day.
매일 당신의 상태.
You're not taking your medicine nor meals.
약도 안 먹고 식사도 안 해요.
If this continues, your health will be affected.
이런 일이 계속되면 건강에 영향을 미치게 됩니다.
Don't try to blackmail me
나한테 협박하려고 하지마
with the people beside me.
내 옆에 있는 사람들과 함께.
Taozi and I are like sisters.
Taozi와 나는 자매 같아요.
We know each other's conditions
서로의 조건을 알아요
the best.
최고.
It has nothing to do with you.
그것은 당신과 아무 관련이 없습니다.
Since you're still mad at me,
아직도 나한테 화났으니까.
I'll leave first.
나는 먼저 떠날 것이다.
Don't sleep with anger, okay?
화를 내며 잠들지 마세요, 그렇죠?
It's bad for your health.
건강에 좋지 않습니다.
Taozi!
도자!
Taozi.
도자.
Let me carry it for you.
제가 대신 운반해 드리겠습니다.
Taozi,
타오지,
are you still angry at me?
아직도 나한테 화났어?
Can you please talk to me?
나에게 얘기 좀 해주실 수 있나요?
Taozi, are you going to gather herbs?
도자님, 약초를 채취할 건가요?
Let me tag along.
나도 따라갈게.
Taozi.
도자.
His Majesty conferred me the title of Lord Qin,
폐하께서 나에게 진공(秦君)이라는 칭호를 주셨으니,
appointed me as Commander-in-Chief,
나를 총사령관으로 임명했다.
and ordered me to reclaim Xichang?
그리고 나에게 시창을 되찾으라고 명령했다고요?
The imperial edict arrived here last night.
어젯밤에 제국의 칙령이 여기에 도착했습니다.
Not only did he confer the title of Lord Qin to you,
그는 당신에게 진공이라는 칭호를 부여했을 뿐만 아니라 ,
but he also conferred the titles of Lord Qi and Lord Xin
그러나 그는 또한 치 경과 신경이라는 칭호도 부여했습니다.
to Lord Kuaiji and Lord Linzi respectively.
각각 Kuaiji 경과 Linzi 경에게.
They're putting me on open fire here.
그들은 나를 여기서 불태우고 있어요.
If I fail to reclaim Xichang,
내가 서창을 되찾지 못하면
I'll be punished, huh?
난 벌을 받을 거야, 응?
Shiqi,
시치,
why don't you refuse it?
왜 거절하지 않는거야?
Refuse what?
무엇을 거부합니까?
Since His Majesty already issued an edict,
폐하께서 이미 칙령을 내리셨 으므로
I'll be Lord Qin then.
그러면 나는 진 경이 될 것이다.
Now,
지금,
as the Commander-in-Chief,
총사령관으로서,
I can dispatch the loyalists
충성파를 파견할 수 있어요
officially
공무상
to reclaim Xichang.
시창을 되찾기 위해.
This time, I'll leave the city to you guys.
이번에는 여러분에게 도시를 맡기겠습니다.
Don't worry, Mister Shiqi.
걱정하지 마세요, Shiqi 씨.
We'll definitely follow your instructions
우리는 반드시 당신의 지시를 따를 것입니다
and flip Xichang
그리고 시창을 뒤집으세요
upside down.
상하 반전.
Precisely.
정확하게.
We might not be good at other things,
우리는 다른 일을 잘하지 못할 수도 있지만,
but flipping places upside down
하지만 장소를 거꾸로 뒤집는 건
is our expertise.
우리의 전문 지식입니다.
It's a shame that I haven't fully recovered yet.
아직 완전히 회복되지 못한 것이 안타깝습니다 .
I can't join you guys this time.
이번에는 여러분과 함께 할 수 없습니다.
I'll go ahead
내가 먼저 갈게
and do your share for you.
그리고 당신을 위해 당신의 몫을 해주세요.
There's an undercurrent surging.
저류가 급증하고 있습니다.
We can't tell friends from foes.
우리는 적과 친구를 구분할 수 없습니다.
You guys must be careful.
여러분, 조심해야 합니다.
Must act cautiously.
신중하게 행동해야 합니다.
And, you must ensure your own safety.
그리고, 자신의 안전을 확보해야 합니다.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
Once we take down Xichang,
Xichang을 쓰러뜨리고 나면,
we'll come back and drink with you.
우리는 다시 와서 당신과 함께 마실 것입니다.
Let's drink!
마시자!
We'll conquer Xichang and drink together when we're back!
시창을 정복 하고 돌아가면 같이 술을 마시자!
Let's drink together!
같이 마시자!
Let's go.
갑시다.
Prime Minister Gu,
구 국무총리,
wild rumors have been spreading in the city.
도시에는 터무니없는 소문이 퍼졌습니다.
There's a hike in food prices,
식료품 가격이 인상됐어요.
and the people are panicking.
사람들은 당황하고 있습니다.
They say that the army Grand Governor
육군 대지 사라고 하는데
had sent to conquer Baiyue suffered a major defeat.
백월을 정복하기 위해 파견되었으나 큰 패배를 당했다.
They were also saying
그들도 이렇게 말하더군요
that Li Ni, the son of the fake emperor, was conferred the title of Lord Qin.
가짜 황제의 아들인 리니(Li Ni)가 진(秦) 공이라는 칭호를 받았다는 것입니다.
And now, he's going to attack Xichang.
그리고 이제 그는 Xichang을 공격하려고 합니다.
People say that he was born
사람들은 그가 태어났다고 말해요
to jinx Grand Governor.
그랜드 주지사를 징크스합니다.
What else did you hear?
또 무엇을 들었나요?
They even said Lord Qin sent his spies here
심지어 진 공이 그의 정탐꾼을 이곳으로 보냈다고 도 했습니다.
to poison the well water.
우물물을 독살하기 위해.
People are panicking.
사람들은 당황하고 있습니다.
They dare not consume well water anymore.
그들은 더 이상 감히 우물물을 마시지 않습니다 .
Some even said
어떤 사람들은 이렇게 말했습니다.
that the granary was empty.
창고가 비어 있었다는 것입니다.
There was no food inside.
안에는 음식이 없었습니다.
They said
그들은 말했다
the army that was sent to Baiyue
백월에 파견된 군대
had already taken all of them.
이미 다 가져갔습니다.
Once...
한 번...
Once Lord Qin surrounds our city,
진 공이 우리 도시를 포위하면
the people in the city
도시의 사람들
will starve to death.
굶어 죽을 것이다.
All right. I understand. You may leave.
괜찮은. 이해합니다. 떠날 수도 있습니다.
Order our servants to guard the door. Don't let anyone out.
우리 하인들에게 문을 지키라고 명령하세요. 누구도 내보내지 마세요.
Yes, Prime Minister.
네, 총리님.
Do you understand now?
이제 이해가 되셨나요?
Is Lord Qin trying to cause a ruckus here?
진 경이 여기서 소란을 일으키려고 하는 걸까요?
That's right.
좋아요.
Lord Qin wants to sow discord among the people.
진공은 백성들 사이에 불화를 심고 싶어합니다.
Now, let's see what the person inside the palace will do
이제 궁궐 안에 있는 사람이 무엇을 할지 볼까요?
to deal with this situation.
이 상황을 처리하기 위해.
Capture all those who were spreading the rumors
루머 퍼뜨린 놈들 다 잡아라
and kill them.
그리고 그들을 죽여라.
Grand Governor,
그랜드 주지사,
I'm afraid the rumor-spreaders have an ulterior motive.
유언비어를 퍼뜨리는 사람들에게는 뭔가 숨은 동기가 있는 것 같습니다 .
That's why we have to kill them.
그렇기 때문에 우리는 그들을 죽여야 합니다.
Not only will I kill them,
나는 그들을 죽일 뿐만 아니라,
but I'll also exterminate their families and clans.
그러나 나는 그들의 가족과 종족도 멸절시킬 것이다.
I'll see
내가 볼게
who's daring enough
누가 충분히 대담한가
to do something like this after this.
나중에 이런 일을 하려고요.
Yes, Grand Governor.
네, 그랜드 주지사님.
Why are you so early today?
오늘은 왜 이렇게 일찍 왔나요?
You didn't like to use rouge in the past.
당신은 과거에 루즈를 사용하는 것을 좋아하지 않았습니다 .
What's with the sudden fondness?
갑자기 좋아하는 건 뭐죠?
Maybe it was because of
아마도 그것 때문이었을 것이다.
the white hair
흰머리
I saw in the mirror that day.
나는 그날 거울을 보았다.
Jing,
징,
are you troubled by court affairs?
법원 업무 때문에 고민이신가요?
You don't need to tell me about them.
그들에 대해 나에게 말할 필요는 없습니다.
Let's go and take a walk.
가서 산책하자.
Ever since I took up arms,
내가 무기를 잡은 이후로,
I always thought
나는 항상 생각했다
that the world
그 세상
could be conquered easily.
쉽게 정복할 수 있었습니다.
I never expected
난 전혀 예상하지 못했어
Li Ni to lead the Zhenxi Army
리니(Li Ni)가 진시군(Zhenxi Army)을 이끌게 된다
all the way here.
여기까지.
He's targeting Xichang now.
그는 지금 Xichang을 목표로 삼고 있습니다.
Tong Pass is the gate to the two capitals.
통관(Tong Pass)은 두 수도로 통하는 관문이다 .
As long as we own Tong Pass,
통패스를 보유하고 있는 한,
it's useless even if
해도 소용없어
Li Ni owns Luoyang.
Li Ni는 Luoyang을 소유하고 있습니다.
Cui Yi is devious and cunning.
Cui Yi는 사악하고 교활합니다.
If he joins hands with Li Ni,
리니와 손을 잡으면
it'll be tough for us.
우리에게는 힘들 것입니다.
That won't happen.
그런 일은 일어나지 않을 것입니다.
Cui Yi has an ulterior motive.
Cui Yi에게는 숨은 동기가 있습니다.
If not, he wouldn't have sent his army out of Yingzhou.
그렇지 않았다면 그는 영주에서 군대를 파견하지 않았을 것입니다.
Li Ni is the son of the fake emperor.
Li Ni는 가짜 황제의 아들입니다.
They harbor different motives.
그들은 서로 다른 동기를 품고 있습니다.
They won't join hands that easily.
그들은 그렇게 쉽게 손을 잡지 못할 것이다.
I shouldn't have told you about that.
나는 그것에 대해 당신에게 말하지 말았어야 했어요.
Come, let's play some polo.
자, 폴로 좀 치자.
Okay.
좋아요.
What? You plan
무엇? 당신은 계획
to ignore me for the rest of your life?
평생 나를 무시할 생각이냐?
Lord Qin, you're overthinking it.
진 경, 당신은 너무 생각하고 계십니다.
You were just conferred the title of Lord Qin.
당신은 방금 진경이라는 칭호를 받았습니다 .
There are plenty of people who wish to gain your favor.
당신의 호의를 얻고 싶어하는 사람들이 많이 있습니다 .
Your Highness, you don't need to care about me.
전하, 제게 신경쓰실 필요는 없습니다 .
In the past, you call me the imperial grandson.
예전에는 저를 황손자라고 부르셨어요.
Now, you call me Your Highness.
이제 저를 폐하라고 부르세요.
Aren't you willing
당신은 의향이 없나요?
to call me Shiqi again?
다시 Shiqi라고 부르라고요?
This place is the best.
이곳이 최고입니다.
When I was young,
내가 어렸을 때,
my nanny said
내 유모가 말했어
that I should make a bamboo dragonfly
대나무 잠자리를 만들어야 한다고
whenever I have a wish.
소원이 있을 때마다.
My wish will be granted
내 소원은 이뤄질 거야
when it falls to the ground.
땅에 떨어졌을 때.
Back then,
그때는,
I wanted to see my mother very badly.
나는 어머니를 몹시 보고 싶었습니다.
Everyone had a mother, except for me.
나만 빼고 모두 어머니가 계셨다.
Thus,
따라서,
I made plenty of bamboo dragonflies.
대나무 잠자리를 잔뜩 만들었어요.
I scaled to the top of the wall and released them one by one.
벽의 꼭대기까지 크기를 조정 하고 하나씩 풀어주었습니다.
When I was done,
내가 끝났을 때,
I found out that my nanny was saying that just to coax me.
나는 내 유모가 단지 나를 달래기 위해 그런 말을 하고 있다는 것을 알게 되었습니다 .
That wish of mine
내 그 소원
could never be fulfilled
결코 충족될 수 없었습니다
no matter how many bamboo dragonflies I made.
내가 얼마나 많은 대나무 잠자리를 만들어도.
People say
사람들은 말한다
that one wouldn't repeat
그 사람은 반복하지 않을거야
their silly mistakes again.
또 그들의 어리석은 실수.
Even so, I still made plenty of bamboo dragonflies.
그럼에도 불구하고 나는 여전히 대나무 잠자리를 많이 만들었습니다 .
Because it's you.
왜냐하면 당신이니까요.
For you,
당신을 위한,
I'm willing to do all the silly things in the world.
나는 세상의 모든 어리석은 일을 기꺼이 할 것입니다 .
Ying,
잉,
can you please forgive me?
저를 용서해 주실 수 있나요?
I promise,
약속해요
from now on,
지금부터,
I won't misunderstand your intention.
나는 당신의 의도를 오해하지 않을 것입니다.
If so, you should stop trapping me here.
그렇다면 나를 여기에 가두는 것을 그만둬야 합니다.
Release me and Taozi back to Yingzhou.
나와 Taozi를 Yingzhou로 돌려 보내주십시오.
I can't allow that.
나는 그것을 허용할 수 없습니다.
If so,
그렇다면,
I have nothing to say to you.
나는 당신에게 할 말이 없습니다.
You're still in the mood to fish, huh?
아직도 낚시할 기분이군요, 그렇죠?
What's wrong?
뭐가 문제 야?
Is Cui Yi's main army here?
최이의 주군이 여기 있나요?
Not yet.
아직 아님.
They're taking their sweet time.
그들은 즐거운 시간을 보내고 있습니다.
Shiqi,
시치,
don't you think
너는 생각하지 않니?
Cui Yi has an ulterior motive?
최이에게 숨은 동기가 있나요?
The situation in Xichang is ever-changing.
시창(Xichang)의 상황은 끊임없이 변화하고 있습니다.
If he doesn't hurry up,
그 사람이 서두르지 않으면,
I'm afraid we'll miss out
우리가 놓칠까 봐 두려워요
on this opportunity.
이번 기회에.
I coerced him into doing this.
나는 그에게 그렇게 하도록 강요했습니다.
Of course he's unhappy to do so.
물론 그는 그렇게 하는 것이 불만스럽습니다.
Besides,
게다가,
he has the number advantage.
그는 수적 우위를 갖고 있다.
But he has to try his best to conquer the city.
하지만 그는 도시를 정복하기 위해 최선을 다해야 합니다 .
Do you think he'll be willing to hurry when he's in that situation?
그 사람이 그런 상황에 처했을 때 기꺼이 서두르겠다고 생각하나요 ?
I just received news.
방금 소식을 받았습니다.
Great General is already...
위대한 장군님은 이미...
This is a rare opportunity indeed.
참으로 흔치 않은 기회입니다.
Maybe we can
아마도 우리는 할 수 있을 것이다
use this chance to escape.
이 기회를 이용해 탈출하세요.
Lieutenant He, I knew you could
그 중위, 난 당신이 할 수 있다는 걸 알았어
think of a great idea.
좋은 생각을 생각해 보세요.
However, we need to plan this out.
그러나 우리는 이것을 계획해야 합니다.
Li Ni is very intelligent.
Li Ni는 매우 똑똑합니다.
It's difficult for us to escape
우리는 탈출하기 어렵습니다
without a thorough plan.
철저한 계획 없이.
Where's Li Ni?
리니는 어디 있지?
Ear has been following me all day long.
귀는 하루 종일 나를 따라다녔습니다.
He kept yapping
그 사람은 계속해서 짖어댔다
because I ignored him.
내가 그를 무시했기 때문이다.
He said that Li Ni was fishing by the lake
리니가 호수가에서 낚시를 하고 있다고 하더군요
this afternoon.
오늘 오후.
He even asked me
그 사람이 나한테 물어보기도 했고
if I wanted to have some fresh fish.
신선한 생선을 먹고 싶다면.
He was fishing?
그 사람 낚시 중이었어?
Who's there?
거기 누구 있어요?
Your Highness, it's me.
전하, 저입니다.
Taozi.
도자.
Please come in.
오세요.
Your Highness, General Pei Yuan.
폐하, 페이위안 장군님.
Your Highness,
전하,
Lieutenant He was taking medicine every day.
중위는 매일 약을 먹고 있었어요.
She didn't take much food either.
그녀는 음식도 많이 먹지 않았습니다.
She has lost a lot of weight.
그녀는 체중이 많이 줄었습니다.
You knew that too.
당신도 그걸 알고 있었죠.
After she took her medicine,
그녀는 약을 먹은 후,
she suddenly said she wanted to have fish ball soup.
그녀는 갑자기 피시볼 수프를 먹고 싶다고 말했습니다.
I asked the kitchen about it.
주방에 물어보니
But they said the marketplace was closed today.
그런데 오늘 장터가 문을 닫았다 고 하더군요 .
They only bought some vegetables.
그들은 야채만 샀어요.
Coincidentally,
우연히도,
I saw some fish
물고기를 좀 봤어
in the bucket.
양동이에.
But they said
하지만 그들은 말했다
those were the fish
저거 물고기였어
you caught by the lake today.
당신은 오늘 호수에 잡혔어요.
I dare not use them without your permission.
나는 당신의 허락 없이는 감히 그것을 사용하지 않습니다.
That's why I came here to ask for your permission.
그래서 내가 당신의 허락을 구하러 여기까지 왔습니다.
Finally she has an appetite,
드디어 식욕이 생겼다.
I'll make the fish ball soup.
제가 피시볼 수프를 만들게요.
No need for that.
그럴 필요는 없습니다.
I can make it.
나는 해낼 수 있다.
It's fine.
괜찮아.
It takes skills to make fish balls.
피시볼을 만들려면 기술이 필요합니다.
Let me do it.
내가 해보자.
If that's the case,
그렇다면,
Your Highness, please go ahead.
전하, 어서 가십시오.
Taozi, you're back.
타오지, 당신이 돌아왔어요.
Yeah, I'm back.
응, 돌아왔어
Try it while it's hot.
더울 때 시도해 보세요.
It'll smell fishy when it gets cold.
추워지면 비릿한 냄새가 나겠죠.
Is it nice?
좋은가요?
It's pretty fresh.
꽤 신선해요.
You should
당신은해야
rest and recuperate.
휴식을 취하고 회복하십시오.
Even if you're mad at me,
나한테 화를 내더라도,
you have to cherish your body.
몸을 소중히 여겨야 합니다.
In the future,
미래에,
just tell me what you want
그냥 네가 원하는 걸 말해봐
and what you wish to eat.
그리고 먹고 싶은 것.
I'll get them for you.
내가 가져다 드릴게요.
Aren't you afraid that I'll use this chance
내가 이 기회를 이용할까 두렵지 않니?
to relay a message back home
집에 메시지를 전달하기 위해
and escape from this place?
여기서 탈출할까?
Even if you do escape from here,
여기서 탈출하더라도
I can intercept you
나는 당신을 차단할 수 있습니다
and bring you back.
그리고 당신을 다시 데려오세요.
If you don't believe me,
당신이 나를 믿지 않는다면,
feel free to give it a try.
자유롭게 시도해 보세요.
The army Sun Jing had sent to Baiyue
손정이 백월에 보낸 군대
didn't really suffer a defeat.
실제로 패배하지는 않았습니다.
Only his army in Yingzhou suffered a defeat.
Yingzhou의 그의 군대만이 패배했습니다.
I'm afraid Sun Jing will recall
Sun Jing이 기억할까봐 두렵습니다.
his army in Baiyue.
바이웨에 있는 그의 군대.
And, he owns Tong Pass.
그리고, 통패스를 소유하고 있습니다.
You're caught in a pincer attack.
당신은 협공 공격을 받았습니다.
Unless
하지 않는 한
you can conquer Xichang
너는 시창을 정복할 수 있다
before the army in Baiyue
바이웨 군대 앞에서
comes back.
돌아오다.
However, I'm afraid
그러나 나는 두려워한다
the Zhenxi Army
진시군
is incapable of such a feat at the moment.
현재로서는 그러한 위업을 수행할 수 없습니다 .
Excellent point.
훌륭한 지적입니다.
However,
하지만,
I still won't release you.
나는 아직도 당신을 석방하지 않을 것입니다.
Your Highness, you do know me well, huh?
전하, 저를 잘 아시죠?
You know me well too.
당신도 나를 잘 알잖아요.
We're the same.
우리는 동일합니다.
Taozi, have you managed to buy everything you need?
Taozi, 필요한 모든 것을 구입 하셨나요 ?
That incident was so long ago.
그 사건은 너무 오래 전 일이에요.
Can you please talk to me?
나에게 얘기 좀 해주실 수 있나요?
I'll do anything for you
나는 당신을 위해 무엇이든 할 것입니다
as long as you talk to me.
당신이 나에게 얘기하는 한.
Don't you know why I'm ignoring you?
내가 왜 당신을 무시하는지 모르시나요?
Back then, you were just observing us
그땐 너도 우리를 관찰하고 있었잖아
when Lieutenant He and I were under pursuit.
그 사람과 내가 추격을 받고 있었을 때요.
You guys ignored us.
너희들은 우리를 무시했다.
You're just like Lord Qin.
당신은 진 진(秦) 경과 같습니다.
You guys are heartless, indifferent,
너희들은 무정하고 무관심하고
and cold-hearted!
그리고 냉정한!
That's not it.
그게 아닙니다.
I was anxious too.
나도 불안했다.
I wanted to rush down and save you.
달려가서 당신을 구하고 싶었어요 .
But it was a military order. I...
그러나 그것은 군사 명령이었습니다. 나...
I had no choice.
나는 선택의 여지가 없었다.
Besides,
게다가,
the soldiers of the Zhenxi Army
진시군 병사들
never go against military orders.
절대로 군사 명령을 거스르지 마십시오.
Your excuses.
당신의 변명.
I'm not making up excuses.
나는 변명하지 않습니다.
That day,
그 날,
Mister Shiqi knew what he was doing.
Shiqi 씨는 자신이 무엇을 하고 있는지 알고 있었습니다.
He had his bow drawn.
그는 활을 뽑았습니다.
He wouldn't just stand there and see you hurt.
그 사람은 그냥 거기 서서 당신이 상처받는 걸 보고만 있을 것 같지 않았어요.
Taozi.
도자.
What exactly do you want me to do before you'll forgive me?
당신이 나를 용서하기 전에 내가 정확히 무엇을 하기를 바라시나요 ?
Why don't I gather herbs with you
당신과 함께 약초를 모으는 게 어때요?
or buy something nice for you?
아니면 당신에게 좋은 것을 사나요?
Do you want to have pig ears?
돼지 귀를 갖고 싶나요?
I'll do anything you like as long as you stop ignoring me.
당신이 나를 무시하지 않는 한 나는 당신이 원하는 것은 무엇이든 할 것입니다 .
Really?
정말?
Anything?
아무것?
Except for releasing you and Lieutenant He.
당신과 그 중위를 석방하는 것만 빼고요 .
You have good hearing, right?
당신은 청력이 좋죠?
Don't tell me
나에게 말하지 마세요
you want to have my ears?
내 귀 갖고 싶어?
Nonsense.
무의미한 말.
Who wants to have your stupid ears?
누가 당신의 멍청한 귀를 갖고 싶어하나요?
I just
난 그냥
want you
널 원해
to make a whistle for me.
나를 위해 휘파람을 불려고요.
A whistle?
휘파람?
I want you to make a whistle that only you can hear.
오직 당신만이 들을 수 있는 휘파람 소리를 들려주세요 .
If I need your help
당신의 도움이 필요하다면
for any emergencies,
어떤 긴급 상황에도 대비해,
I'll blow the whistle.
휘파람을 불겠습니다.
That sounds difficult.
어려운 것 같네요.
But don't worry.
하지만 걱정하지 마세요.
I can definitely make it for you.
나는 확실히 당신을 위해 그것을 만들 수 있습니다.
That's more like it.
그게 더 비슷해요.
So, Taozi, you'll stop ignoring me, right?
그럼 도자야, 이제 더 이상 나를 무시하지 않을 거지?
You are not angry at me, right?
당신은 나에게 화를 내지 않았죠?
That depends on my mood.
그건 내 기분에 따라 달라요.
Mister Shiqi went to see Lieutenant He just now.
Shiqi 씨는 방금 허 중위를 만나러갔습니다 .
She shut the door on him again.
그녀는 그에게 다시 문을 닫았습니다.
He deserved it.
그는 그럴 자격이 있었습니다.
Miss Taozi,
미스 타오지,
actually, Mister Shiqi
사실, Shiqi 씨는
is very nice to Lieutenant He.
그는 중위에게 매우 친절합니다.
Why don't you speak up
왜 말을 안 해?
for him in front of her
그녀 앞에서 그를 위해
and try to appease her?
그리고 그녀를 달래려고?
If he was
만약 그가 그랬다면
truly nice to Lieutenant He,
그 중위님 정말 친절하시네요.
he wouldn't just use these random herbs to brew her medicine.
그는 그녀의 약을 만들기 위해 이 무작위 약초를 사용하지 않을 것입니다 .
Even now, Lieutenant He hasn't recovered from her injuries.
지금도 허 중위는 부상에서 회복되지 않았습니다.
Look. What are these?
바라보다. 이것들은 무엇입니까?
Miss Taozi, don't be angry.
타오자 선생님, 화내지 마세요.
Well, give me the prescription.
자, 처방전을 주세요.
I'll buy the herbs.
제가 허브를 사겠습니다.
If I can't buy them nearby,
근처에서 못 사면
I'll buy them in Xichang or Luoyang, OK?
시창이나 뤄양에서 살게요, 알았죠?
You said so yourself.
당신 스스로도 그렇게 말했지요.
Fine.
괜찮은.
I'll get you the prescription right now.
지금 바로 처방전을 가져다 드리겠습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Keep fanning it. Don't stop.
계속해서 부채질을 해주세요. 멈추지 마세요.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Lieutenant He hasn't recovered from her injuries.
중위는 부상에서 아직 회복되지 않았습니다 .
The herbs here are limited.
이곳의 허브는 제한되어 있습니다.
So Miss Taozi gave me a prescription.
그래서 Taozi 선생님이 나에게 처방전을 주셨습니다.
She told me to buy these herbs.
그녀는 나에게 이 약초를 사오라고 말했습니다.
By the way, Taozi also said
그런데 도자(Taozi)도 말했다.
that she would speak up for you
그 사람이 당신을 대신해 말해줄 거라고
in front of Lieutenant He
허 중위 앞에서
as long as I buy all of these herbs.
내가 이 허브들을 모두 사는 한.
Dragon bone,
용뼈,
Forsythia suspensa,
개나리 정지,
Aesculus hippocastanum,
Aesculus hippocastanum
pumice, ephedra,
경석, 에페드라,
and Fritillaria pallidiflora?
그리고 Fritillaria pallidiflora?
That's a lot of herbs.
허브가 많이 들어있네요.
And, she even designated the stores.
그리고 매장까지 지정해 주셨어요.
The stores are far away from each other too.
매장 도 서로 멀리 떨어져 있어요.
Taozi said
도자가 말했다.
she knew which store sold the best herbs.
그녀는 어느 가게가 최고의 허브를 파는지 알고 있었습니다.
If I try
내가 시도하면
to brush her off,
그녀를 털어내려고,
she won't let me off when she finds out.
그녀는 그 사실을 알더라도 나를 놓아주지 않을 것입니다.
Good job.
잘했어요.
I'll go now.
나는 지금 갈 것이다.
Taozi didn't tell you
Taozi는 당신에게 말하지 않았습니다
to buy them one by one, right?
하나씩 사려고 하는 거 맞죠?
Isn't it faster
더 빠르지 않은가
if you get help?
도움을 받는다면?
This is a request from Miss Taozi.
타오즈 선생님의 부탁입니다.
How could I tell other people to do it?
어떻게 다른 사람들에게 그렇게 하라고 말할 수 있나요?
Besides, it's just a few stores.
게다가 매장도 몇 개 안 돼요.
I travel fast. It won't take up much time.
나는 빨리 여행한다. 시간이 많이 걸리지 않습니다.
I'll be leaving now.
나는 지금 떠날 것이다.
(Huichun Apothecary) Huichen Apothecary? I finally found it.
(회춘약국) 회천약국? 드디어 찾았어요.
Shopkeeper,
가게 주인,
I want to buy this.
나는 이것을 사고 싶다.
Aesculus hippocastanum.
Aesculus hippocastanus.
(Huichun Apothecary) (Aesculus hippocastanum)
(Huichun Apothecary) (Aesculus hippocastanum)
Here are your herbs.
여기 약초가 있습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Here's the money. Keep the change.
여기 돈이 있습니다. 잔돈.
Take care.
잘 지내세요.
Miss Taozi!
미스 타오즈!
I bought all the herbs.
허브를 다 샀어요.
That quickly?
그렇게 빨리?
Did you skive and skip some of them?
그 중 일부를 건너뛰고 건너뛰셨나요?
I didn't!
나는하지 않았다!
I bought them one by one
하나씩 샀어요
according to your list.
당신의 목록에 따르면.
Let me see.
어디 보자.
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
Miss Taozi,
미스 타오지,
can you please
부탁할 수 있나요
speak up for Mister Shiqi
Shiqi 씨를 대신해 말해주세요
in front of Lieutenant He then?
그럼 그 중위 앞에서요?
Fine.
괜찮은.
I'll do it on account of these herbs.
이 약초 때문에 그렇게 할게요.
Let me check them again.
다시 확인해 보겠습니다.
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
Ying.
잉.
The weather is pretty good today.
오늘은 날씨가 꽤 좋습니다.
I got you some osmanthus.
오스만투스를 좀 사다 드렸어요.
Ying?
잉?
I'll leave it at your doorstep then.
그럼 문앞에 두고 가겠습니다.
♪If I forget the fleeting of time♪
♪덧없는 시간을 잊어버린다면♪
♪Waiting for memories to shatter and sink♪
♪추억이 부서지고 가라앉기를 기다리며 ♪
♪The emotional scars in your heart♪
♪마음 속 감정의 상처♪
♪Are the entanglement I find hard to let go of♪
♪ 놓기 힘든 얽힘인가 ♪
♪If longing is not forgotten♪
♪그리움이 잊혀지지 않는다면♪
♪I long to return to the very first moment♪
♪나는 처음의 순간으로 돌아가고 싶다 ♪
♪The affection we had in our fateful situation♪
♪ 운명적인 상황 속에서도 우리가 가졌던 애정 ♪
♪How I wish to keep it for you♪
♪당신을 위해 그것을 간직하고 싶습니다♪
♪If love still remembers the promises we made♪
♪사랑이 우리가 한 약속을 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪Despite going against fate, I have no regrets loving you♪
♪운명을 거스르면서도 당신을 사랑한 걸 후회하지 않아요♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪당신을 위해 기꺼이 희생하겠습니다♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪당신의 대답을 기다리면서♪
Lieutenant He,
그 중위,
we have fresh flowers again today.
오늘도 싱싱한 꽃이 있어요.
I'll swap yesterday's bouquet for this one.
어제 부케를 이것으로 바꿀게요 .
Lieutenant He, you should stop being mad.
중위님, 그만 화내세요.
I think Lord Qin...
내 생각엔 진왕님...
No.
아니요.
I mean he's apologizing to you sincerely this time.
이번에는 진심 으로 사과한다는 뜻이에요 .
Didn't he say
그 사람이 말하지 않았나요?
that he wasn't supposed to trust you?
그 사람이 당신을 믿으면 안 된다고 했죠?
Actually, Cui Li was the one
사실 최리(Cui Li)가 그 사람이었어요
behind Young Master's passing.
Young Master의 죽음 뒤에.
It's not his fault.
그의 잘못이 아닙니다.
Strange.
이상한.
Why are you
너는 왜
speaking up for him today?
오늘 그 사람 대신해서 얘기할 거야?
Lieutenant He,
그 중위,
I'm doing this for your sake.
나는 당신을 위해 이 일을 하고 있습니다.
I think Lord Qin
내 생각엔 진(秦) 경이
is truly nice to you.
정말 친절해요.
He even sent his men to buy herbs from various stores.
그는 심지어 여러 상점에서 약초를 사도록 부하들을 보냈습니다 .
He still wants to keep you company here
그 사람은 아직도 당신과 함께 있고 싶어해요
even if you show him a long face
그에게 긴 얼굴을 보여도
every day.
매일.
Actually,
실제로,
I know that he's sincere in apologizing to me too.
나는 그 사람이 나에게도 진심으로 사과한다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
I should stop being mad at him.
그 사람한테 화내는 걸 그만둬야겠어.
I wouldn't be this angry
이렇게 화내진 않을 텐데
if someone else did this.
다른 사람이 이런 짓을 했다면.
But...
하지만...
To me, he's different from
나에게 그 사람은 다른 사람이다.
other people.
다른 사람.
I see.
알겠어요.
I was wondering why.
왜 그런지 궁금했습니다.
I'll get angry if you keep that up.
계속 그렇게 하면 화를 낼 것 같아요.
It's my fault.
그것은 내 잘못이야.
Don't be angry.
화내지 마세요.
I'll change your flowers for you.
당신을 위해 꽃을 바꿔드릴게요.
Great General.
위대한 장군.
We've received news.
소식을 받았습니다.
(Xichang)
(시창)
Mister Shiqi!
시치씨!
Mister Shiqi, I have good news.
Shiqi 씨, 좋은 소식이 있어요.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Taozi said
도자가 말했다.
she finally convinced
그녀는 마침내 확신했다
Lieutenant He to see you
중위가 당신을 만나러 왔어요
after all the effort she has put in.
그녀가 쏟은 모든 노력 끝에.
Tonight, they'll hold a banquet beside the lotus pond.
오늘 밤 그들은 연꽃 연못 옆에서 연회를 열 예정이다.
By then, Taozi will act accordingly
그때쯤이면 Taozi는 그에 따라 행동할 것입니다.
and give you two a chance to speak in private.
두 사람 에게 개인적으로 말할 기회를 주세요 .
By the way, Taozi also said
그런데 도자(Taozi)도 말했다.
that all women
그 모든 여자들은
are soft-hearted.
마음이 여린 편이다.
By then, you need to apologize to her
그때쯤이면 그 사람한테 사과해야지
sincerely.
감사합니다.
This way,
이 방법,
Lieutenant He can be appeased.
중위는 진정될 수 있어요.
Thank Miss Taozi for me.
나를 위해 Miss Taozi에게 감사드립니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
♪If I forget the fleeting of time♪
♪덧없는 시간을 잊어버린다면♪
♪Waiting for memories♪
♪추억을 기다리며♪
♪To shatter and sink♪
♪부서지고 가라앉도록♪
♪The emotional scars in your heart♪
♪마음 속 감정의 상처♪
♪Are the entanglement♪
♪얽혀 있군요♪
♪I find hard to let go of♪
♪놓기가 힘들어요♪
♪If longing is not forgotten♪
♪그리움이 잊혀지지 않는다면♪
♪I long to return to the very first moment♪
♪나는 처음의 순간으로 돌아가고 싶다 ♪
♪The affection we had in our fateful situation♪
♪ 운명적인 상황 속에서도 우리가 가졌던 애정 ♪
♪How I wish to keep it for you♪
♪당신을 위해 그것을 간직하고 싶습니다♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪The promises we made♪
♪우리가 한 약속♪
♪Even if this love hurts me♪
♪이 사랑이 나를 아프게 해도♪
♪I'll continue living for you♪
♪나는 계속 당신을 위해 살아갈게요♪
♪Holding onto the memories♪
♪추억을 붙잡고♪
♪Waiting is my persistence♪
♪기다림은 나의 끈기♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪사랑이 기억한다면♪
♪The promise I made to you♪
♪너와 한 약속♪
♪Despite going against fate♪
♪운명에도 불구하고♪
♪I have no regrets loving you♪
♪당신을 사랑한 걸 후회하지 않아요♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪당신을 위해 기꺼이 희생하겠습니다♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪당신의 대답을 기다리면서♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪사랑이 기억한다면♪
♪The promise I made to you♪
♪너와 한 약속♪
♪Despite going against fate♪
♪운명에도 불구하고♪
♪I have no regrets loving you♪
♪당신을 사랑한 걸 후회하지 않아요♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪당신을 위해 기꺼이 희생하겠습니다♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪당신의 대답을 기다리면서♪